<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-12T15:58:52-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kathryn P. Mercier</title><subtitle>Biogeography, Evolution, Conservation</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Some things I didn’t know before (applying to) grad school - in no particular order</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/08/What-I-didn't-know.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some things I didn't know before (applying to) grad school - in no particular order" /><published>2019-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/08/What-I-didn't-know</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/08/What-I-didn't-know.html">&lt;p&gt;I am writing this list down for two reasons. First - in case there are other people out there, who like me, didn’t know these things. Maybe this list can provide someone with a bit of information they didn’t have before. Or maybe they have already figured these things out through experience, and we can just feel a little less alone hehe. Second - I am writing this for future me. (Hi future Kathryn! Hope the future is a less bleak than it seems!). I want to be able to remember what it was like before I knew what I know now. Stick with me - most of us tend to forget what we didn’t know. For example, it might be difficult to explain your science to non-scientists because they don’t know what a niche is and you can’t even comprehend not knowing what a niche is! I want to avoid getting out of touch, by remembering what I didn’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That your advisor should be an author on your poster presentation when they’re funding your work (sorry Chris - fixed this one quickly!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being ‘first-generation’ was a category, and could be used to my benefit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could get PAID to go to school&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks were not the only beneficial thing to happen at conferences&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That grad school wasn’t just another series of classes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grants which fund research and grants which fund you (through stipends) both exist&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why many of my undergrad teachers kind of sucked at teaching. They weren’t being judged by their teaching, they were being judged on their research&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How crucial communicating (written and oral) your science is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That you apply to work ‘with people’ not ‘at institutions’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything I’ve learned before is wrong, and no one knows anything for sure (a literal thing I tweeted my first year)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can make a timeline… but then multiple how long each item should take by like ten… at least&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That post-docs were a thing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a community inside AND outside of grad school is essential for your mental health&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much good presentation slides can improve audience comprehension (this could be a whole ‘nother post)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am writing this list down for two reasons. First - in case there are other people out there, who like me, didn’t know these things. Maybe this list can provide someone with a bit of information they didn’t have before. Or maybe they have already figured these things out through experience, and we can just feel a little less alone hehe. Second - I am writing this for future me. (Hi future Kathryn! Hope the future is a less bleak than it seems!). I want to be able to remember what it was like before I knew what I know now. Stick with me - most of us tend to forget what we didn’t know. For example, it might be difficult to explain your science to non-scientists because they don’t know what a niche is and you can’t even comprehend not knowing what a niche is! I want to avoid getting out of touch, by remembering what I didn’t know.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Grad School Visits - some advice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/24/GradSchoolVisits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grad School Visits - some advice" /><published>2019-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/24/GradSchoolVisits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/24/GradSchoolVisits.html">&lt;p&gt;I am at the airport, waiting for my flight home after the first semester of my PhD. This time last year I was visiting prospective labs; for any anyone starting that process now I want to share questions you should consider asking prospective advisors and lab mates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, most important: Are you happy? This is a question for everyone you meet! You can ask more specific things like: Are you happy in this lab, in this department, in this city? People will be honest, and you can start to get an idea if you would be happy there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another good general question: What changes do you see occurring in the lab/department in the near future? For me, this helped to get a sense of department priorities. I was looking for answers around diversity &amp;amp; inclusion, because we can all do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some questions for advisors. What makes up a PhD? What is your mentoring style? What do you expect from students day to day? How are students typically supported? How do students fund their theses/dissertations? How do you maintain work life/balance?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q’s for potential labmates. All the questions from ⬆️, get their perspective on advisor. What is time to graduation? Where are recent grads working? Is there collaboration within/between labs? Is there travel support, for field or conferences? What is the lab/office space?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General grad students q’s. How accessible/social are faculty? What is the process to candidacy &amp;amp; defense? What do you teach? Where do you live? How affordable is the city? Do you feel prepared for job market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure to ask about things that are going to be important for your research or career: training for teaching, or available supercomputing, or what lab equipment is available. What classes are offered and do the students like them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course, probably don’t ask everyone all of these questions. Make sure to ask people about themselves, about their research and what they do outside of the lab! Have fun and try to make some new connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**This was originally posted on my Twitter: @kpmercier&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am at the airport, waiting for my flight home after the first semester of my PhD. This time last year I was visiting prospective labs; for any anyone starting that process now I want to share questions you should consider asking prospective advisors and lab mates! First, most important: Are you happy? This is a question for everyone you meet! You can ask more specific things like: Are you happy in this lab, in this department, in this city? People will be honest, and you can start to get an idea if you would be happy there.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/04/Hello-World.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New website" /><published>2018-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/04/Hello-World</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/04/Hello-World.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my new website! I am in the process of migrating my website from 
&lt;a href=&quot;www.kpmercier.wixsite.com/home&quot;&gt;Wix&lt;/a&gt;, so please bear with me while the dust settles. 
This site is built using GitHub Pages, and is based on 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/barryclark/jekyll-now&quot;&gt;Jekyll Now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Welcome to my new website! I am in the process of migrating my website from Wix, so please bear with me while the dust settles. This site is built using GitHub Pages, and is based on Jekyll Now.</summary></entry></feed>